state.ok.us 2002-06-09

# yourOklahoma - Official State Website

Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Purpose**

The purpose of the statement is to inform users of yourOklahoma about the collection and use of personally identifiable information.

**Definition of Personally Identifiable Information**

For the purposes of this statement "personally identifiable information" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable individual who is the subject of the information

**Personally Identifiable Information Not Routinely Collected**

Citizens are not asked to routinely provide personal information to visit Oklahoma web sites or to download information. Government agencies may request personally identifiable information from you in order to provide requested specialized services, but such information is handled as it would be on an in-person visit to a government office.

**Personally Identifiable Information Available From Governmental Web Sites**

Access to personally identifiable information in public records at state and local levels of government in Oklahoma is controlled by Oklahoma law. Information that is generally available under Oklahoma law may be posted for electronic access through yourOklahoma.

The IP (Internet Protocol) numbers of computers (servers) used to visit yourOklahoma sites are noted as part of our statistical analysis on use of our web sites so we may better design services and improve access to them. However, the site does not attempt to gain personally identifiable information on individual users and associate them with IP addresses

**Use of Constituent E-mail Addresses**

E-mail addresses obtained as a result of a request to the state site will not be sold or given to private companies for marketing purposes. The information collected is subject to the access and confidentiality provisions of Oklahoma Code and federal law. E-mail or other information requests sent to the state web site may be maintained in order to respond to the request, forward that request to the appropriate agency, communicate updates to the state page that may be of interest to citizens, or to provide the yourOklahoma Web designer with valuable customer feedback to assist in improving the site. Individuals will be provided with the ability to "opt out" at anytime of any communication regarding new service updates.

**Data Security and Quality**

YourOklahoma is committed to data security and the data quality of personally identifiable information that is either available from or collected by governmental web sites, and has taken reasonable precautions to protect personally identifiable information from loss, misuse or alteration. Any third parties responsible for this information are committed to the same principles, and also are required by contract to follow the same policies and guidelines as the state of Oklahoma in protecting this information. Unless otherwise prohibited by state or federal law, rule or regulation, the individual is granted the ability to access and correct personally identifiable information whether or not the information inaccuracy was accidental or by created unauthorized access.

**Non State Web Sites**

Various Web sites may be linked through yourOklahoma. Visitors to those sites are advised to check the privacy statements of these sites and be cautious about providing personally identifiable information without a clear understanding of how the information will be used.

YourOklahoma is managed by NICUSA, Inc.
